Guide to the Marjorie T. Duck Environmental Collection, 1973-1995 AIS.1999.05
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Marjorie T. Duck Environmental Collection
1973-1995
1977-1991
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Duck, Marjorie T.
AIS.1999.05
1.25 Linear Feet
The Marjorie T. Duck Environmental Collection is composed of publications related to the environmentalist movement. The records date from 1973-1995.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Marjorie T. Duck on September 3, 2000.
Biography
Starting in the 1970's, Marjorie Thompson Duck worked in support of environmentalist causes of both national and local importance to Eastern Pennsylvania. Her personal interest in clean energy led to her involvement in an organization dedicated to environmental outreach in local schools. In the organization Mrs. Duck served as librarian and collected educational materials. The name of the organization and the exact time frame of Ms. Duck's involvement is not known.
Previous Citation
Marjorie T. Duck Environmental Collection, 1973-1995, AIS.1999.05, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Scope and Content Notes
The Marjorie T. Duck Environmental Collection consists predominately of publications and printed material on issues related to energy production and the proposed installation of a hazardous waste incinerator in Allenwood, Pennsylvania. The materials range in date from 1973 to 1995.
Arrangement
The Marge Duck Environmental Collection is arranged into two series:
Series I. Energy, 1973-1991
Series II. Hazardous Waste Incinerator, 1986-1995
Incinerators; Hazardous wastes -- Incineration; Environmentalists; Environment; Solar energy; Social action; Environmental protection; Green movement; Environmentalism; Nuclear energy; Duck, Marjorie T.
- Energy, I.
  Scope and Content Notes
  This series contains publications and printed pamphlets related to a host of energy related subjects. These subjects include: anti-nuclear energy publications, consumer energy saving guides, environmental organization energy publications, individual viewpoints on energy, local government energy strategy, passive solar energy research studies, pro-solar energy publications, Pennsylvania state government energy strategy, and sustainable design.
  - Anti-Nuclear Energy Publications, 1973-1977 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Consumer Energy Saving Guides, 1977-1991 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Environmental Organizations, 1976-1991 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Local Government Energy Strategy, 1975-1978 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Passive Solar Energy Research Studies, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Pennsylvania State Government Energy Strategy, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Pro-Solar Energy Publications, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Sustainable Design, 1977 - 1992 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Viewpoints on Energy, 1977 - Circa 1985 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Hazardous Waste Incinerator, II.
  This series contains materials relating to proposals to build a hazardous waste incinerator in Allenwood, PA. The series is divided into two folders. The first folder contains primarily public relations material issued by USPCI Inc., a Union Pacific subsidiary that wanted to build and operate the hazardous waste incinerator. The materials date from 1986-1995, years when the incinerator plans were going through the approval process through state government. The plan for the incinerator was supported by the Department of Environmental Resources(DER)but ultimately failed. The second folder contains newsletters from Organizations United for the Environment (OUE) voicing opposition to the construction of the incinerator through their "Ban the Burner" campaign.
  - Corporate Public Relations Material, 1986-1991 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Environmental Organization Newsletters, 1991-1995 (Box 2, Folder 11)